Robert A. Taft Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Miscellany, 1907-1953 (Box 1384-1434)
  - Eternity Fish and Game Club, St. Felix d'Otis, Chicoutimi County, Quebec, Canada (Box 1410)
    - 1929-1943, (6 folders)
    - 1944-1947, (4 folders) (Box 1411)
    - Bank statements
      - 1933-1934
      - 1935-1940, (2 folders) (Box 1412)
    - Bank statements and correspondence, 1933-1940, (2 folders)
    - Bouchard, Elie Philippe, 1932-1940
    - Checkbook, 1932-1940 (Box 1413)
    - Current leases and copies, 1935
    - Financial matters, 1933-1935
    - General correspondence, 1933-1940, (2 folders)
    - Girard lawsuit, 1932-1933 (Box 1414)
    - Government correspondence, 1933-1940
    - Insurance, 1934-1943
    - Leases of fishing rights and membership cards, 1931-1935
    - Maps, 1936
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1940
      - 1946-1953 (Box 1415)
    - Old leases, 1916-1935
    - Old and new constitution and bylaws, 1930-1934
    - Receipts, 1933-1940
  - Form letters
    - 1944-1947, (2 folders)
    - 1948-1943, (4 folders) (Box 1416)
  - A Foreign Policy for Americans (Box 1417)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1953
    - Galley proof, 1951
    - Miscellaneous, 1951
  - Get-well messages, 1953 (Box 1418)
    - A-E, (6 folders)
    - F-L, (7 folders) (Box 1419)
    - M-R, (5 folders) (Box 1420)
    - S-Z, (6 folders) (Box 1421)
  - Gifts, 1944-1952, (3 folders) (Box 1422)
  - Memorabilia (Box 1423)
    - Biographical material, 1952
    - College notes, 1909-1910, undated
    - Miscellaneous, undated, (2 folders)
    - Souvenir program
    - Taft, William H., 1938-1940
  - Messages of Martha Bowers Taft (Box 1424)
    - Get-well cards and notes, 1950, (3 folders)
    - Ladies of the Senate, Washington, D.C., 1937-1940
  - Pointe-au-Pic, Quebec, Canada, material (vacation home) (Box 1425)
    - 1947-1953, undated, (2 folders)
    - Banking, 1951
    - Miscellaneous, 1939, 1951
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn. (Box 1426)
    - 1936-1939, (5 folders)
    - 1940-1943, (4 folders) (Box 1427)
    - 1943-1948, (4 folders) (Box 1428)
    - 1948-1949, (4 folders) (Box 1429)
    - 1949-1951, (5 folders) (Box 1430)
    - 1952-1953, (5 folders) (Box 1431)
    - 1953 (Box 1432)
    - Clippings, 1906-1910
    - Corporation
      - 1945-1946, (3 folders)
      - 1946 (Box 1433)
    - Dramatic Association, 1915-1946
    - Emerson, Thomas I., 1946
    - Examination and miscellaneous, 1906-1910
    - Glee Club and pageant, 1914-1917
    - Glee Club, seats, 1917
    - Law school fund, 1952 (Box 1434)
    - Miscellaneous, 1906-1910
    - Plays and programs, 1907-1910
    - Reports, 1947
    - Security portfolio, 1939
    - Sports and Class Day, 1907-1910
- Addition, 1910-1980 (Box 1435-1451)
  Family papers, general correspondence, political material, speeches and writings, business papers, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged in order of the preceding eleven series and thereunder alphabetically by type of material or name of person, organization, or subject.
  - Family papers (Box 1435)
    - Taft, Charles Phelps, obituaries, 1930
    - Taft, Helen Herron
      - Business papers
        - Estate papers, 1910, 1930-1933, 1942-1960, undated, (2 folders)
      - Mortgages
        - A-H, 1934-1951, (5 folders)
        - I-Z, 1934-1950, (10 folders) (Box 1436)
        - Real estate, 1938-1943, (3 folders) (Box 1437)
      - Correspondence with Robert A. Taft, 1923, 1932
    - Taft, Martha Bowers
      - Business papers
        - Estate papers
          - Accounts, 1958-63
          - General correspondence, 1919, 1954-62, undated, (2 folders)
          - Investments, 1916-1962, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 1438)
          - Permanent file, 1958-1962, undated
          - Thomas Wilson Trust, 1940-1941, 1952-1959, undated, (2 folders)
          - Wills, letters testamentary, and powers of attorney, 1930, 1953-1958
        - Household and farm matters, 1953-1960
        - Insurance, 1947-1960
        - Taxes
          - Fiduciary, 1958-1963
          - Income
            - 1942-1944, (3 folders)
            - 1945-1958, (7 folders) (Box 1439)
          - Personal property, 1942, 1952-1962
      - Clippings, 1928-1940, undated
      - Death
        - Letters of condolence, 1958, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 1440)
        - Obituaries, 1958
      - Political file, correspondence
        - 1924-1939
        - 1940, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 1441)
        - 1941-1952, undated, (4 folders)
      - Speeches and writings file
        - Background information, 1938-1949, undated, (2 folders)
        - Biographical material, 1938-1949, undated
        - Itineraries and schedules, 1940-1949, undated
        - Related correspondence, 1940-1949, undated (Box 1442)
        - Speeches, 1939-1949, undated, (5 folders)
    - Taft, Robert (1917-1993)
      - Taft, Martha Bowers, letters written on behalf of, 1953-1961
      - Taft, Robert A., letters from the public regarding, 1960-1974, (2 folders) (Box 1443)
    - Taft, William H.
      - Business papers, estate papers, 1925-1933, undated, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence with Robert A. Taft, 1917-28
      - Death
        - Memorial in Arlington National Cemetery (stele), Washington, D.C., 1930-40, undated See also Oversize, (2 folders)
        - Obituaries, 1930
        - Resolutions in honor of Taft, 1930-1931
    - Taft, William Howard (1915 Aug. 7), clippings, 1953
  - General correspondence (Box 1444)
    - Groll, Fred L., 1942-1948
    - Hollister, John B., 1939-1940
    - Kent, Frank, 1940
    - Kirk, Muriel, 1940-1949, undated
    - Rowe, Dorothy Snowden, 1938-1952
    - Unidentified, undated
  - Political file
    - Campaign literature, 1939-1950, undated
    - Campaign songs, 1952, undated
    - General, 1948-1950
  - Speeches and writings file
    - Press releases, 1950
    - Speeches
      - Alphabetical file
        - List
        - Civil rights, 1939, 1964-1965
        - Communism, 1952
        - Foreign policy and national defense, 1941, 1950-1953, 1963
        - Korean crisis, 1950
        - Legislation, 1946-1951
        - Liberty, 1939-1953
        - National economy, 1938-1952
        - National health insurance, 1946-1949
        - Political morality and honesty in government, 1950-51
        - Principles of the Republican party, 1946-1952
        - Public housing, 1943-1969
        - United Nations, 1944-1964
      - Chronological file, 1939-1953, undated, (7 folders) (Box 1445)
    - Writings, A Foreign Policy for American, autographed hardcopy, 1951
  - Business papers (Box 1446)
    - Estate papers
      - Correspondence
        - Donations, 1953-1954
        - General, 1956-1967
      - General, 1916, 1926-1931, 1952-1961, (4 folders)
      - Investments, 1950-1959, undated
      - Permanent file, 1953-1964, (2 folders)
      - Taxes (Box 1447)
        - Estate and inheritance, 1953-1957, undated
        - Fiduciary and personal property, 1953-1960
        - Personal property and real estate, District of Columbia, 1943-1955
        - Valuation of securities for tax purposes, 1941-57, undated
      - Washington, D.C., residences, 1953-1955, undated, (2 folders)
    - Income taxes, 1943-1948, (6 folders)
    - Indian Hill Acres, Cincinnati, 1932-1950 (Box 1448)
  - Miscellany
    - Biographical material, 1939-1968, undated
    - Clippings
      - General, 1938-1963, (8 folders)
      - Scrapbook, 1952-1954 (Box 1449)
    - Commercial Club of Cincinnati, "The Club Dinner, Christmas Season 1899," William H. Taft played by Robert A. Taft, 1949
    - Death
      - Funeral list, 1953
      - Letters of condolence, 1953
        - To Martha Bowers Taft, (3 folders)
        - To Robert Taft (1917-93), (2 folders) (Box 1450)
      - Memorials
        - Bust on stele, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1957-1961
        - Statue and carillon, Washington, D.C., 1959
      - Obituaries and tributes, 1953, (2 folders)
      - Resolutions in honor of Robert A. Taft, 1953 See also Oversize, (2 folders)
    - Get-well messages, 1953, (1 folder) (Box 1451)
    - Interview with Stanley and Dorothy Snowden Rowe, Senator Robert A. Taft Project, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 1968
    - National health insurance, 1949-1963
    - Photographs, 1938, 1959, undated
    - Public housing, 1968
    - Robert A. Taft Institute of Government, New York, N.Y., 1963
    - Writings about Taft, 1953-1980
- Oversize, 1919-1953 (Box OV 1-OV 3)
  Awards, certificates, memorial resolutions, photostatic copies, and scrapbooks.
  Arranged and described according to the series and containers from which the items were removed.
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Awards and certificates, 1919-1943 (Container 1388)
  - Addition
    - Miscellany
      - Death
        - Resolutions in honor of Robert A. Taft, 1953 (Container 1450)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 2)
    - Photostatic copies, 1949 (Container 1393)
    - Scrapbooks, 1940-1950 (Container 1393), (2 vols.); (1 vol.) (Box OV 3)
- Top Secret, 1948-1949 (Box TS 1)
  Material containing security classified information.
  Arranged and described according to the series, container, and folder from which the items were removed.
  - Subject file (Box TS 1)
    - 1948
      - Trip abroad, talks on Germany, 1948-1949 (Container 899)